World War II Servicemen from Branford College, Yale University, Corespondence, and Manuscript of "We Minded the Store" by Polly S. Buck
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Correspondence of World War II servicemen from Branford College, Yale University, and the manuscript of by Polly S. Buck
1942-1975
RU 812
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1
(3 boxes)
The materials include the letters of World War II servicemen from Branford College (Yale) to Polly S. Buck, who was wife of the master; letters to various recipients from John William Ruff (Yale 1927), who was a Professor of English at Yale and a fellow of Branford College before the war; and permission to publish correspondence. Also included is a manuscript of Buck's book, We Minded the Store.
Buck, Polly Stone
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 42-C (YRG 42-C), Materials documenting military and wartime experiences of members of the Yale community.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged in four series: I. General Correspondence, 1943-1946. II. William Ruff Correspondence, 1942-1946. III. Permission to Publish Correspondence, 1969-1975. IV. Manuscript Draft of We Minded the Store.
Scope and Contents
The World War II letters were given to the Archives by Polly Stone Buck, who as the wife of Dean Buck, Master of Branford College, corresponded during the world war with servicemen from Branford College. A few years later she wrote the book We Minded the Store documenting the war years at Branford College and the war experiences of Branford men.
The materials have been processed both chronologically and alphabetically. Series I includes general correspondence, chronologically filed to retain the sequence of events of war, from servicemen who wrote once or twice a year. Series II includes the chronological correspondence of William Ruff. This exception was made because these letters were sent to several different people and give insight into one man's frustration with the service. An explanation of who the recipients were appears in the permission to publish folder for William Ruff.
Series III includes permission to publish correspondence and is alphabetically arranged. It contains typed quotes from the men's letters, for which many times Mrs. Buck asks for more thorough explanations, and of course there are the updates of the intervening twenty five years. Access to each individual's wartime letters is possible as the dates of these appear on the front of his permission to publish letter.
A draft of We Minded the Store comprises Series IV.
Photographs which came to the Archives with these materials have been placed in the Yale Picture Collection, YRG 48-A-1.
Biographical / Historical
Polly S. Buck was the wife of the Branford College master, Norman Sydney Buck. During World War II she corresponded with servicemen from her college. Her book, We Minded the Store (1975), documents the war years at Yale and the war experiences of men of Branford College.
Soldiers -- United States; World War, 1939-1945 -- Personal narratives, American; Buck, Polly Stone; Ruff, John William -- 1905-; Branford College (Yale University); Yale University -- Alumni and alumnae; Yale University -- Faculty
- General Correspondence, 1943-1946, undated; Series I
  - 1943 January-August (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1943 September-Dec, [1943?] (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1944 January-August (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1944 September-December (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1945 January-April (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1945 January-April (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1945 September-Dec, [1945?] (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1946 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - WW II Christmas cards, Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- William Ruff Correspondence, 1942-1945; Series II
  - 1942 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 1943 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 1944 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - 1945 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Permission to Publish Correspondence, 1969-1975; Series III
  - Allen, Greer (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Allen, William F. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Aiken, George (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Baker, Wilder D. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Bachman, Roger A. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Barker, Allen (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Barr, Andrew (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Bartholomew, Marshall (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Booth, Robert (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Bowers, A. Margaret (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Britton, Thomas C. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Brown, R. Wells (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Buck, Pierpont B. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Burke, Basil C. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Caulfield, James D. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Chace, Burton E. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Chapman, John D. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Clement, John C. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Collins, John (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Cronmiller, Bruce (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Daggett, David (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Dappert, George (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - de Capua, A. George (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Diamond, Eddie (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Diamond, Frank B. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Downey, Russell H. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Drake, Harold E. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Dyke, Robert (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - English, Chester F., Jr. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Farrar, Curtis (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Fitt, Alfred B. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Flink, Stanley E. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Fowler, Herbert K. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Gabriels, A. G., Jr. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Goodwin, Ralph T., Jr. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Greer, J. Taylor (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Guba, Philip M. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Hamilton, Ralph A. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Harris, Edward M., Jr. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Harpole, Charles (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Heizer, Raymond (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Hess, Merrill (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Holmes, George (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Horchner, Richard (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Huff, George F. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Huff, William S. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Jenkins, Richard E. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Joralemon, Peter (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Klein, Randall (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Kitchen, Richard S., Sr. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Lamb, Lomax B., Jr. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Ledes, John. (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Lincoln, William L. (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Liverance, Melville P. (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Logan, Lawther (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Logan, L. B. C. (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Low, Richard F. (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Mac Cabe, Lynn (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - McCarty, Franklin B. (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Mac Eachron, David (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - McLellan, David S. (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Matthews, Joseph O. (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Matthews, Samuel W. (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Monroe, Willys H. (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Motz, Henry (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Nolte, Richard H. (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - O'Donnell, Edward D. (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Ortner, Robert C. (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Peak, Helen (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Peltz, William (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Pitt, Theodore K. (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Pomeroy, Harlan (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Price, Lorin E. (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Richardson, Arleigh D., III (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Rowe, George (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Ruff, William (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Shank, Richard (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Sheldon, Albert M. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Sherry, John (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Shively, George C. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Smith, Edward H. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Smith, Richard (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Smith, Thomas B. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Spilner, Robert (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Stiff, John S. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Stimola, Michael (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Swan, Judge Thomas W. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Tatterson, Donald H. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Van Cortlandt, Augustus, III [mother of] (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Vigneron, E. Morgan, Jr. (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Waite, Leslie S., Jr. (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Walsh, Philip C. (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Warren, George U. (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Waterson, Frederick W., III (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Wells, Carl Robert (Bob) (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Wilkie, Valleau (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Younger, George D. (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Zamboni, Frank J. (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Zeller, Anna K. (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Manuscript of We Minded the Store, Series IV
  - Chapters 1-21 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Chapters 22-39 (Box 3, Folder 32)